<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recurrent events on Lili Wang&#39;s Research Page</title>
    <link>https://lilywang1988.github.io/tags/recurrent-events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recurrent events on Lili Wang&#39;s Research Page</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy {2019}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://lilywang1988.github.io/tags/recurrent-events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Penalized Survival Models for the Analysis of Alternating Recurrent Event Data</title>
      <link>https://lilywang1988.github.io/project/bivppl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lilywang1988.github.io/project/bivppl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recurrent event data are widely encountered in clinical and observational studies. Most methods for recurrent events treat the outcome as a point process and, as such, neglect any associated event duration. This generally leads to a less informative and potentially biased analysis. We propose a joint model for the recurrent event rate (of incidence) and duration. The two processes are linked through a bivariate normal frailty. For example, when the event is hospitalization, we can treat the time to admission and length-of-stay as two alternating recurrent events. In our method, the regression parameters are estimated through a penalized partial likelihood, and the variance-covariance matrix of the frailty is estimated through a recursive estimating formula. Simulation results demonstrate that our method provides accurate parameter estimation, with relatively fast computation time. We illustrate the methods through an analysis of hospitalizations among end-stage renal disease patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
